Mother,
母親
I've drafted the abdication decree.
退位令書已經寫好了
Now I only need the City Owner Seal.
就差您的城主印了
This is the most thoughtful thing
這是你自小以來
you've ever done so far.
做得最妥帖 最周全的一件事
Thank you for your compliment!
謝母親誇獎
Since you've forged the decree,
連退位令書都能偽造
why didn't you forge a City Owner Seal at the same time?
你何不再偽造個城主印呢
It should be very easy to you.
多簡單的一件事啊
You know that these are all forgeable,
您既然知道這些都可以偽造
so this fake decree is obviously
那單憑這一封可以造假的令書
not convincing enough.
又如何服眾
Why don't you
不如母親
just help me this one last time?
您再幫我最後一次
Walk out of here
從這裡走出去
and announce in the meeting hall
在議事廳當眾宣佈
that you'll pass your throne to me,
您讓位於我
and demote Chen Qianqian to a commoner.
廢陳芊芊於庶人
You told me
您不是也說過嗎
that you've been raising me as your successor.
您一直把我當繼承人來培養
"The City Owner of Huayuan
花垣城主治理城邦
has ruled the city for 25 years.
已二十有五載
Though the city was once in turmoil,
曾遭遇動盪
with the blessing of our great ancestors,
然幸賴祖宗之靈
it was revitalized again.
危而復興
After observing the astrological signs and people's will,
仰瞻天文 俯察民心
though people's support is there,
今民心雖在
The City Owner is in a bad shape
城主卻身體抱恙
and no longer capable to lead the future of Huayuan.
無力支撐花垣城未來
The Third Princess Chen Qianqian
三郡主陳芊芊
was appointed as the Crown Princess,
雖獲封少城主
yet she is ill-behaved and has no sense of morality.
奈何其品行不端 道德淪喪
She's not a good fit for the position,
不堪大任
and she's not
遠不及二郡主陳楚楚
as large-hearted and caring as Chen Chuchu, the Second Princess.
宅心仁厚 心繫百姓
You are large-hearted and caring?
好一個宅心仁厚 心繫百姓
And she is ill-behaved and has no sense of morality?
好一個道德淪喪 品行不端
Do you know
你知道嗎
that when you were born,
當年你出生的時候
Huayuan and Xuanhu were right at war.
正是花垣 玄虎兩城交戰之時
To rescue Huayuan City,
裴司軍為了保全花垣城
Minister Pei sacrificed her life.
以身殉職
At that moment, I made up my mind
當時我就想
to raise you into a righteous person like her.
把你培養得像她那樣剛正
Later on, you were really more and more like her.
後來 你越來越像她
If
如果
you can inherit Huayuan
你能繼承花垣城
and become the next City Owner,
繼任城主之位
I think you'd live up to your capabilities.
也算是賢能者居之
Why did you
母親何故
talk about late Minister Pei?
提起已故裴司軍
I...
我
I just remembered something from the past.
我只是想起了一些往事
I feel sorry that my years of effort
覺得這麼多年的心血
has gone in vain!
我都白費了
Mother, we don't have so much time!
母親 時間差不多了
Do you remember how the corner of this seal
你還記得這印上這個角
was damaged?
是怎麼缺的嗎
When you were little,
當年你小的時候
you thought it was a toy and tossed it around.
拿著它當玩具 拋著玩
Then you accidentally chipped the corner.
不小心磕掉了一個角
But I didn't blame you at all.
我也 沒有怪罪你
I didn't expect
沒想到
that when you touched it again,
你再摸到它
you'd use it
卻用它做了
to do such an unfilial and disloyal thing!
這樣不忠不孝的事情
If I had known it,
早知今日
I should have punished you severely
當初 我就該重重地罰你
and let you know the gravity of misbehavior!
讓你知道 什麼叫大逆不道
At this point,
事已至此
it's too late to change my mind!
我已經回不了頭了
Your Majesty!
城主
You... you dare to threaten me?
你 你敢威脅我
Mother, just grant my request!
母親 您就成全女兒這一次吧
You!
你
Give it to me!
給我
Chuchu!
楚楚
Your Highness! Young Master Han betrayed us!
二郡主 韓少君反水了
Our people
我們的人
have been surrounded by Xuanhu army!
已經被玄虎護城軍控制了
What?
什麼
Han Shuo tricked me!
韓爍居然敢算計我
You idiot! You opened the door to our enemy?
你這個引狼入室的蠢貨
Han Shuo is a crafty person!
韓爍此人心機頗深
You are not his match at all!
豈是你能駕馭的
Only Qianqian can contain him!
只有芊芊才可以
Han Shuo!
韓爍
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
城主 城主
Han Shuo, you promised you'd work with me,
韓爍 你嘴上說與我聯手
but you betrayed me while I was negotiating with my mother!
卻在我與母親周旋之際出賣我
It's only because you are too credulous,
是二郡主太容易輕信別人
just like how I was before.
就像曾經的我一樣
Chen Qianqian was the one who lied to you!
騙你的人是陳芊芊
My heart for you is real!
我一腔真情
How can you treat me like this because of her mistake?
你卻因為她的過錯這般對我
You should blame that you are all women of Huayuan.
怪只怪你們都是花垣女人
So you only have Chen Qianqian
難道你的心中
in your heart?
就只有陳芊芊嗎
Your Highness!
二郡主
Stop!
住手
Pei Heng, you stole the flower token?
裴恆 你偷了花符
Arrest Han Shuo, now!
立刻將韓爍拿下
The City Guards' job is to protect Her Majesty and Huayuan City.
護城軍護城主 保花垣
We'll never disgrace the fame of Pei family!
從來不會辱沒裴家的聲名
Looks like between your mother and me,
看來 在我與你母親之間
you chose your mother.
你選擇了你母親
Between Huayuan and me,
在我與花垣之間
you chose Huayuan.
你選擇了花垣
Han Shuo.
韓爍
My love for you
我對你的情意
and my intention of protecting Huayuan citizens
跟我要保護花垣子民這件事情上
are not against each other.
並不衝突
Do you understand?
你能明白嗎
Arrest them all!
把他們拿下
Report!
報
Minister Pei!
裴司軍
A group of bandits helped us take the city gate back!
一群山匪助我們拿下了城門
Bandits?
山匪
Could it be Meng Guo?
難道是孟過
Meng Guo!
孟過
How did we forget about him?!
怎麼把他給忘了
Young Master, it'll be too late if we don't go now.
少君 再不走就來不及了
There's still one thing I need.
我還有樣東西沒拿
When we conquer Huayuan,
等我們佔領了花垣
the Crown Princess will belong to you sooner or later!
少城主早晚是您的
Qianqian, come with me!
芊芊 跟我走
Stop!
住手
Mother!
母親
Arrest Han Shuo and Chen Chuchu!
將韓爍 陳楚楚拿下
Chuchu,
楚楚
from now on, I'm no longer
你我二人之間的母女情分
your mother!
就此了結
Maybe I owed you
也許一開始
in the beginning,
是我欠了你的
but now, we are even!
可現在 我們兩清了
Your Highness, did you receive my letter?
少城主 我的信您收到了吧
Han Shuo, Her Highness asked me to follow you,
韓爍 少城主派我跟著你
but you escaped!
卻讓你逃了
I'll capture you again today
今日我要將你重新擒住
to fulfill my mission that Her Highness assigned to me!
不枉少城主囑託
Han Shuo,
韓爍
please stop!
收手吧
You mean
你說
Han Shuo was the principal criminal,
韓爍是主犯
and Chuchu was his hostage?
楚楚是人質
Chuchu has been a prudent and sensible person.
楚楚向來謹慎懂事
If she weren't threatened,
若不是被歹人脅迫
she wouldn't have rebelled.
必不會做出圍府之事
She tried to stab Qianqian
她最後 向芊芊刺的那一劍
because she wanted to prevent Han Shuo from escaping.
也是為了阻止韓爍逃走
You stole the flower token from Chuchu.
偷走楚楚花符的人是你
Why are you trying to save her now?
現在替她開脫的人也是你
Even if I'm not,
就算我不替她開脫
I think you'll still forgive her
想必 您也會網開一面
and spare her life.
饒她不死
Rebellion is a serious sin!
覬覦城主之位可是大錯
Why do you assume that I'd let her go?
你怎麼知道我會放她一馬
Because she's the only daughter of the late Minister Pei!
憑她是已故裴司軍唯一的女兒
Because you promised my mother
憑您曾對我母親承諾
that you'd take good care of Chuchu!
會好生對待楚楚
How did you know that?
你怎麼知道此事
My mother died in battle.
當年我母親戰死
Chuchu was a baby and you pitied her,
您可憐楚楚年幼
so you adopted her.
將她帶回府中親自撫養
Back then, I was already old enough to remember things.
那時 我已經記事了
But now,
可如今
Chuchu made a big mistake.
楚楚已經鑄成大錯
Let Han Shuo die for her.
讓韓爍替她死
Once Han Shuo is dead,
韓爍一死
no one else will know the truth.
便能堵住悠悠眾口
Chuchu could be an accomplice,
楚楚 既可以是從犯
could be a hostage,
可以是人質
could even be a heroine
也可以是臥薪嚐膽
who spied for days and finally made her work worth.
最後倒戈的功臣
No matter what, let Han Shuo
總之 要將罪名
take all the blame!
全部推到韓爍頭上
Good!
好
Like mother, like son!
青出於藍勝於藍
You do live up to your mother's reputation!
的確不負你母親的盛名
Though I planned everything,
千算萬算
I forgot about Meng Guo's troop.
還是算漏了孟過那支人馬
I should have listened to Bai Ji
當初真應該聽白芨的
and enlisted Meng Guo into my army.
將孟過收為己用
You finally got what you wanted.
最後還是如你所願了
I'm here to save you!
我是來救你的
You think I can still be saved?
你覺得現在我還能活命嗎
The daughter turned against her mother.
母女反目
The sisters fought each other over the throne.
姐妹奪權
In order to shut my mouth and save her dignity,
花垣城主就算是為了臉面
the City Owner will certainly kill me!
也會將我滅口
You'll live
我讓你活
if I want you to.
你就能活
You think I'll still trust you?
你以為現在我還會信你嗎
Han Shuo,
韓爍
you still don't know
你到現在都不知道
that my love for you is real, do you?
我對你的感情是真是假嗎
I regard myself as a smart person.
我覺得我是個聰明人
But you always make me feel
但每一次都讓我感覺
that I'm just fooling myself.
我是自作聰明
No matter what I want,
無論我想做什麼
I'll end up doing things as you wish.
到最後都會按照你的想法發展
What did I wish?
我想什麼了
♪Use the ink stone to adjust the heavy and light.♪
一尊方硯勾勒濃淡
♪A single word is worth a thousand pieces of gold.♪
一字千金最怕輕淺
♪Paint the mountains and rivers on the paper.♪
澄心紙上畫江山
♪I'm not afraid of storm, but afraid of rumors.♪
風雨無畏畏流言
♪Wake up in the middle of night.♪
醒來的夜半
♪So many ups and downs in life.♪
多少洶湧波瀾
♪Use a chessboard to foresee the future.♪
一方棋盤縱觀福難
♪Win the battle with one strike...♪
一招制敵
Let's do it!
煮飯
♪The black and white are intertwined.♪
黑白兩色且周旋
♪Every move is difficult and there's no chance to regret.♪
落子不易悔亦難
♪I can only decide it on my own...♪
自恃決斷
Qianqian!
芊芊
Mother!
母親
Could you please spare Han Shuo's life?
能不能不殺韓爍
If you must kill him today,
若是今日你一定要殺韓爍
I'll die together with him!
那我就與他一同死在這兒
We are a real couple now!
我與韓爍已經是真正的夫妻了
I'm not lying!
這次我沒有騙你
I really love him!
女兒是真心喜歡他的
I can let Chuchu be the Crown Princess.
我可以把少城主之位給楚楚
With your guide,
有您的教導
I'm sure she'll be a qualified City Owner!
她一定也會是一代賢明的城主
And you can also be relieved.
母親日後也能高枕無憂了
Mother,
母親
just consider that I died on the day
你就當陳芊芊與韓爍成婚當日
I married to Han Shuo.
就已經死了
I'm begging you!
我求求你了
Please spare his life!
求求你 放了韓爍吧
I'm willing to give up everything
只要你放了他
as long as you set him free.
女兒什麼都不要了
Then what about me?
那我呢 我怎麼辦
You won't even want your mother anymore
你竟然為了一個男人
because of this man?
連母親都不要了嗎
Mother, are you happy being a City Owner?
母親 你當城主開心嗎
I never wanted
少城主之位
to be the Crown Princess.
本來就不是我想要的
I only want Han Shuo!
我想要的只有韓爍一人
Then I really need to kill him!
那我更要殺了他
Behead him!
斬
Han Shuo!
韓爍
Qianqian!
芊芊
Hope my death
希望我的死
can put an end
能讓這場禍事
to this mess.
有個結局
Mother, please let Han Shuo go!
請母親放過韓爍
Qianqian!
芊芊
-Qianqian! -Your Highness!
芊芊 三公主
No!
不要
Xiaoqian!
小千
Your Majesty!
城主
Xiaoqian! Xiaoqian!
小千 小千
Qianqian!
芊芊
♪All my life,♪
半生光景
♪I just want to keep you from being lonely.♪
只戀你伶仃
♪I want to settle down and enjoy peace♪
命若浮萍願從此
Qianqian!
芊芊
♪in this life full of uncertainty.♪
寵辱不驚
♪It seems all I have wished for♪
放眼平生的願望
♪is about you.♪
都和你有關
♪I'm at peace knowing that I have you♪
同享悲歡共患難
♪who would stand by my side and share my sorrow.♪
亂世也心安
♪Will you walk into my life♪
趁我餘生未滿
♪while we are still young?♪
可否相結伴
♪Life is sweet as long as you're with me.♪
有你分擔我心甘
♪I hope the dream can come true.♪
盼事圓
Don't look.
別看了
Or you'll be sad.
省得傷心
It's my fault!
是我錯了
I didn't know she loved you this much!
我不知道芊芊她對你用情至斯
To save your life,
為了讓城主赦免於你
she even killed herself!
居然自戕換命
If I had known that,
如果我知道
I wouldn't have stolen the flower token
就不會去偷花符了
and led the City Guards to siege you.
率護城軍圍攻你
You had no choice.
形勢所逼
We represented two different sides.
立場不同
You only did that to rescue Qianqian.
你也是為了救芊芊
And I wouldn't have convinced Her Majesty
也不會獻計城主
to let you take
將所有的罪名
all the blame.
推給你一人
You asked the City Owner to kill me?
是你讓城主殺我
So that was for selfish reasons!
這就完全出於私心了吧
You thought you could
你以為我死了
be with Qianqian after I died?
你就能和芊芊在一起
It's my fault
是我
that Qianqian died!
害芊芊殉情
That's right!
是
It is your fault!
都是因為你
Look!
你看
She'd rather sacrifice her own life
她寧願自己躺在棺材裡
than watch me die
也不願意讓我死
and be with you!
去和你在一起
Didn't you feel ashamed to say something like that?
你還有顏面說這種話
Qianqian killed herself,
芊芊自盡
yet you don't feel sad at all!
你絲毫不見悲痛
Apparently you were just
可見你對她只有欺瞞
fooling and using her!
利用 作弄
I really regret that I didn't get a chance
我恨就恨在
to show Qianqian who you really were
沒讓芊芊認清你的真面目
and let you pay for what you did!
讓你認罪伏法
It is what it is.
事已至此
You and Qianqian weren't meant to be together in this life.
此生你與芊芊無緣
From now on,
此後
just forget about her.
你就忘了她吧
I can't!
忘不了
How can I forget her?
怎麼可能忘呢
I let her wait for too long.
是我讓她等了太久
We were engaged
從兒時起
when we were little.
我倆婚約既定
I should have married her later.
我就應該順應這段姻緣
But I was too young
怪我年輕氣盛
and always stalled our marriage.
一拖再拖
That's why I missed her.
才與她一再錯過
You mean
你的意思是
if you had married her earlier,
如果你早點下手
I wouldn't have had any chance?
就輪不到我了
Men of Xuanhu are all cold-hearted!
玄虎城男子薄情寡義
If I had known things would turn out like this,
早知如此
I wouldn't have let you have her, ever!
我當初就不應該把她讓給你
You let me have her?
你讓的
I fought for her myself!
明明是我自己爭取的
My love for Qianqian is real!
我對芊芊一片真心
But to you, it's worth nothing!
竟被你看成草芥
Real?
真心
Are you willing to die for her?
少君肯為她殉情嗎
Die for her?
殉情
You don't dare!
你不敢
But I do!
但我敢
It's my fault that Qianqian died!
芊芊是我害的
I won't let her
我不會讓她一個人
die alone!
孤單上路
Don't!
別
Hold on a sec!
你等等
Calm down!
別衝動
I'll accompany her!
我去陪她
I asked you to wait!
我讓你等等
Wait!
等等
Pei Heng!
裴恆
Qianqian! Qianqian!
芊芊 芊芊
You are still alive?!
你還活著
It... it was just a prop.
做 做了個道具
I thought it could deceive everybody.
想瞞天過海來著
You faked your death?
你這詐死
We said that we'd keep this a secret.
不是說好騙過所有人
How come you let it slip
怎麼一輪到裴恆
in front of Pei Heng?
你就捨不得
You've pushed him into a corner!
你都快逼死他了
What were you up to?
安的什麼心
Well, I just accidently
這 我就是不小心
said something wrong!
說岔了
Pei Heng, I'm sorry
裴恆 對不起啊
that you had to go through that.
讓你難過了
I really had
我這也是逼不得已
no other choice.
實在沒辦法了
You did this for Han Shuo,
是為了韓爍
as well as to ease
還為了讓楚楚
Chuchu's mind.
放下戒心
Are you going
你是不是
to leave Huayuan City?
要離開花垣城了
Han Shuo,
韓爍
would you please give us a moment?
你出去一下吧
I have something to say to Pei Heng.
我有話要跟裴恆說
I heard
剛才你說的那些話
what you said just now.
我都聽到了
If I had the courage to tell you that earlier,
如果能早點有這種勇氣
things for us might
我們也許不會
be different.
不是今天的模樣
Pei Heng,
裴恆
maybe we didn't belong to each other from the very beginning.
也許我們一開始就不可能
The me you love
你喜歡的那個我
isn't the one you knew
並不是你認識的那個我
or the one you thought I was.
也不是你想象中的那個我
Just pretend that I was poisoned to death
你就當是我大婚當晚
on my wedding night when I drank the cross-cupped wine.
喝交杯酒被毒死了
You hated me back then.
那個時候你還很討厭我的
There's one less eyesore in this world,
世界上少了一個礙眼的人
and no one will force you anymore
你也不用被逼著
to marry someone you don't like.
跟一個不喜歡的人成婚
Maybe thinking of it this way
這樣想想
will make you feel a little better.
你心裡會好受一點嗎
But you didn't die.
可你沒死
Falling in love with you
我活到今日
after your marriage
最慶幸的事
is the best thing that has ever happened
就是在你大婚之後
to me so far.
喜歡上你
It felt like
彷彿我的人生
my life became meaningful
從那一刻起
from that moment on.
才開始有了意義
You were the one who told me
是你告訴我
that I could also have my aspiration,
我可以有我自己的理想
I could do whatever I wanted to do
可以像女子一樣
just like a woman.
做自己喜歡做的事
But later on, I realized
可到後來我才發現
my aspiration,
我的理想
the one I loved the most,
我最喜歡的
was you!
只有你
I didn't know what love was either,
可我也是遇到韓爍之後
until I met Han Shuo.
我才知道愛是什麼滋味的
Pei Heng,
裴恆
you will meet a nice girl in the future.
你以後會遇見一個很好的人
Don't be concerned about me.
所以你不必再牽掛我
I will be fine.
我會過得很好的
Alright.
好
Starting tomorrow,
從明天起
I won't love you anymore.
我就不再喜歡你了
And you don't need to worry about me either.
你也不必再牽掛我了
Okay.
好
It's a deal.
我們一言為定
May you rest in peace, Your Highness!
慢走啊 少城主
What are you doing here?
你來做什麼
Qianqian was my sister after all.
芊芊畢竟是我妹妹
I'm here to offer my condolences.
我來弔唁
She's already
她已經
gone.
死了
She won't fight with you for anything now.
再也不會和你搶什麼了
You are on your own!
你好自為之吧
Say, since Chen Qianqian is dead,
你說 陳芊芊死了
why isn't Pei Heng crying?
裴恆為什麼沒有哭
Zi Zhu,
梓竹
go find some stuff for me.
去幫我找幾樣東西
What were you talking about?
剛才你倆聊什麼呢
Nothing.
沒什麼
Why do you wanna know?
你知道這麼多幹嗎
I'm afraid
我怕
that Pei Heng is still in love with you.
裴恆對你餘情未了
After you pass away,
等到你百年之後
I'll name you
需要諡號的時候
"Xuanhu King of Jealousy"
我就給你取一個 叫
as your posthumous name!
玄虎醋王吧
I think it'll work!
我看行
More people are coming!
大部隊來了
Your Highness!
少城主
Her Majesty, the Princess Royal and the Second Princess
城主 大郡主 二郡主
have all arrived.
都過來弔唁了
Get ready!
你們抓緊啊
Come on, cover me up!
快給我蓋起來
Listen,
我告訴你啊
Chuchu is very smart.
楚楚可精明得很
Don't let my mother find out the truth!
千萬不要讓母親發現了
Come on! Hurry!
快快快 快
How come I think
我怎麼覺得
you are still hiding something from me
你有什麼事瞞著我呢
aside from Pei Heng?
不光裴恆這事
I need to know all of your secrets
我得知道你全部
so that I can feel relieved.
這樣我才安心
Young Master, hurry up!
少君 你們倒是快點
They are here!
人都來了
Okay! Come on, close it up!
行 快快快 蓋起來
We've opened our hearts to each other.
我們倆都坦誠相見了
I'm not keeping anything from you!
那還有什麼事能瞞著你
Close it up, now!
蓋起來
When you lie,
你撒謊的時候
you always look all over the place!
這眼神總是飄忽不定的
You haven't explained
你還沒跟我解釋過
about your Kung Fu.
你武功呢
I will tell you after we get to Xuanhu City, alright?
我到玄虎城再跟你解釋好不好
Just cover me up, now!
你先蓋起來
Come on! We don't have time!
快 來不及了
Okay, then it's a deal!
行 那就說定了
If you lie to me again,
如果你再敢騙我
I'll let you know who wears the pants in our family!
我就要振夫綱了
Don't close it fully! I need to breathe!
給我留條縫
Qianqian!
芊芊
Mother,
母親
shall we take one last look at Qianqian?
我們再看芊芊最後一眼吧
Your Majesty,
城主
you'd better not.
還是別看了
It'll only make you sad.
免得傷心
Mother.
母親
Mother. Qianqian is gone.
母親 芊芊已經去了
You need to take good care of yourself.
您身體為重
Forget it.
罷了
Let's not look at her.
別看了
Just let her rest in peace.
還是讓她歇息吧
Mother,
母親
I have a method that can protect her body from decay
我有一個可保屍身不腐的方法
and make her face remain the way it is.
能讓故去的人 音容永存
What method?
什麼方法
Refine mercury from cinnabar
以丹砂煉製水銀
and inject the mercury into her blood vessels.
灌入血脈
This way, the body will never decay.
可保遺體不朽
She wants to poison me to death!
這不是要毒死我嗎
Qianqian was the Crown Princess of Huayuan!
芊芊生前怎麼說也是少城主
How can you treat her body with disrespect?
怎可對屍身不敬
No.
算了
Just let her rest.
還是讓她安息吧
In that case,
既然如此
I have a nice coffin in my mansion.
我府上有一塊上好的棺木
It's well sealed,
密不透風
insect-repelling and moisture-proof.
可驅蟲防潮
It suits her noble status better.
也顯逝者尊貴
Put Qianqian
一會兒
in that coffin later.
給芊芊換上吧
That coffin is sealed tightly.
棺材封得死死的
I'll suffocate to death
不等韓爍把我挖出來
even before Han Shuo digs me up!
我都憋死了
Qianqian disobeyed Her Majesty;
芊芊忤逆城主
she was a sinner.
算是罪人之身
She doesn't deserve such a nice coffin.
不配用這麼好的棺材
You may as well just save that for yourself!
二郡主還是留著自己用吧
Since she was a sinner,
既然是罪人
then she can't be buried in the tomb of our ancestors.
不能入祖宗陵墓
But mother
但母親
certainly won't let Qianqian wander in the wild
也不可能看著芊芊在外流浪
and become a homeless ghost.
做孤魂野鬼吧
Why don't we cremate her body instead of burying her?
不如就土葬改為火葬
That way, we can make her relics into sarira,
將芊芊煉成一顆舍利
which will be enshrined in the ancestral temple
供奉在祖宗祠堂
to comfort her spirit in heaven.
以慰她在天之靈
She wants to burn me into ashes!
這是想將我灰飛煙滅
She won't even give me a break after I died!
死都不肯放過我
How come
二郡主和芊芊
you hate Qianqian this much?
究竟有何深仇大恨
Han Shuo, you are getting so upset.
韓爍 你如此激動
Are you afraid of anything?
莫不是心虛吧
Maybe
難不成
you did something to Qianqian?
你對芊芊做了什麼手腳
Chen Chuchu!
陳楚楚
She was your sister!
她可是你妹妹
Stop it!
住手
Air! I need air!
空氣 空氣沒了
Qianqian!
芊芊
My daughter!
我的女兒
I'll say goodbye to you now!
母親與你就此訣別
If your spirit can hear me,
你若泉下有靈
please come visit me in my dreams!
就常常到母親的夢裡來
I will offer sacrifices to you
每逢初一十五
on new moon and full moon days.
我會為你祭祀
Your two sisters
你的兩位姐姐
will remember you, too!
也不會忘了你的
Your Majesty! Sorry for your loss!
城主節哀啊
Your Majesty, sorry for your loss!
城主節哀
Mother!
母親
Yuanyuan!
沅沅
Chuchu!
楚楚
You two
以後
are all I have now.
母親就只有你們兩姐妹了
Just let me
芊芊的後事
take care of Qianqian's funeral.
就由我來處理
You may take your leave now.
你們都退下吧
Your Majesty.
城主
Life and death are all destined.
生死有命
Please
您
take care!
身體為重
Han Shuo,
韓爍
Qianqian is making
芊芊為了你
such a big sacrifice for you.
都做到了這種地步
You've got to treat her well!
你一定要好好地待她
Mother
母 母親
just... just left like that?
就 就這麼走了
She wouldn't even say anything more to my body?
她都不對著我的棺材多說兩句
Is she still angry with me?
她是不是還在生我的氣啊
She wouldn't forgive me even I'm dead.
我死了她都不原諒我
She may already know your plan.
她估計都已經知道你的計劃了
What a childish play!
小孩子把戲
Your Majesty, you mean
城主是說
the Third Princess faked her death?
三公主 詐死
If I hadn't played along,
要不是我護著
her trick would've been exposed!
早就露餡了
The Third Princess
這個三公主
is surely stubborn.
也真是任性
She hurt you so badly
為了救韓少君
in order to save Han Shuo's life.
居然惹城主傷心
Not only to save Han Shuo,
她不光是為了韓爍
but also to save Huayuan City.
她也是為了花垣城
From now on, Chuchu
從此以後 我這兒
will be my only successor.
就剩楚楚一個繼承人了
There'll be no more fights.
少了許多的紛爭
Though the citizens of Huayuan support Qianqian,
花垣城百姓擁戴她
Chuchu can't stand her.
可是楚楚容不下她
If she didn't die,
如果她不死
Chuchu and I
我和楚楚之間
would never get along.
就不會相安無事
So the Crown Princess
難道少城主
actually gave up on the City Owner's position?
這是在讓位
Today,
今日
I admitted her death,
我默認了她的死訊
which means we are no longer mother and daughter.
就算是割捨了這段母女情
She betrayed me that day
那天在法場之上
for Han Shuo on the execution ground.
她為了韓爍背棄了我
And today,
而今天
I betrayed her
我在靈堂之上
for Huayuan in the mourning hall.
又為了花垣城背棄了她
I don't know if Qianqian will blame me.
也不知道芊芊會不會怨我
I think she will understand your thoughtfulness.
少城主一定會明白城主的苦心的
But
只是
it'll be difficult for her to return to Huayuan in the future.
再回花垣城那就難了
Don't know when
你們母女相見
you can see each other again.
不知道又是何年月
Escort her to the cemetery tonight
今夜命人護送她到陵園
and offer her a chance to leave.
給她離開的機會
Yes!
是
Her Majesty has ordered
城主已經下令
to bury the Third Princess in the cemetery tonight.
今夜將少城主的壽棺葬入陵園
I'll let her fake death become true
我要讓陳芊芊假死變成真死
and bury her there forever!
永遠葬在那裡
Yes! I will finish this mission.
是 小人一定將此事辦好
Then come back soon.
速去速回
I still need to find a way to take back the flower token.
我還要想辦法把花符拿回來
In fact, if you are promoted to be the Crown Princess,
其實 若二郡主升任少城主
it should be appropriate to appoint Mr. Pei
那司軍一職交給裴公子
as the Minister of Defense.
也算合適
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼
How can a man be qualified to lead the army
男人怎麼有資格帶兵打仗
and command the City Guards?
執掌護城軍
However, when I become the Crown Princess,
不過等我當上少城主
it'll be different.
會不一樣的
I will appoint you as the lieutenant!
我會任命你為副將
I will do my best to serve you, Your Highness!
小人一定盡心輔佐郡主
Go ahead.
去吧
Can you go faster?
能不能快點走啊
I... I'm afraid!
我 我好害怕
It's a little scary in here!
這裡面 有點嚇人
If you are afraid,
你怕的話
I can get in and hold you in my arms.
我進去抱著你
Don't!
別
It'd feel like you bury yourself alive for me.
你進來搞得跟殉葬似的
Plus, the oxygen inside is not enough for two people.
而且這裡面氧氣也不夠
What's oxygen?
氧氣是什麼
It's a type of gas
氧氣就是人活著
on which humans live.
必須要的一種氣體
Without it, people can't survive.
要是沒有 人就活不下去了
Then you are my oxygen!
那你就是我的氧氣
Let her go!
放開她
Su Ziying?
蘇子嬰
Chen Qianqian, you are really alive!
陳芊芊 你果然還沒死
Yingying, please calm down!
嬰嬰 你別衝動
Put... put the sword down.
你 你先把刀放下
I know what you want.
你想要什麼我知道
Just put the sword down.
你放下刀
Let's talk, okay?
咱倆好好聊 好不好
I want you to die!
我想讓你死
Lin Qi!
林七
Lin Qi! You are alive!
林七 你沒死
I haven't got my revenge yet.
我仇還沒報
Of course, I couldn't die!
當然不能死
Did Chen Chuchu send you?
說 是不是陳楚楚派你來的
It doesn't matter who sent me.
誰派我來的不重要
What matters is
重要的是
that all of you should be dead!
你們都不該活著
Just kill me
有本事
if you dare!
殺了我
Look, if you had surrendered to me earlier,
你說你早就歸降於我
there wouldn't be so much trouble!
不就沒這麼多事了
What do you wanna do to him?
你想如何處置他
Your Highness,
少城主
you can also capture and release him seven times respectively.
七擒七縱吧
He will definitely change his ways after that
他一定會改過自新的
and submit to you completely.
對你心服口服
Meng,
孟大哥
Su Ziying is different from you!
蘇子嬰跟你不一樣
I can never catch him again if I release him.
放了他就抓不回來了
Then I'll be after him wherever he goes!
我追他到天涯海角
What do you want to do to him exactly?
到底怎麼處置
Su Ziying tried to kill you several times!
蘇子嬰三翻五次想要置你於死地
He deserves to die!
此人 死不足惜
Wait!
等
Don't... don't kill him!
別 別殺
Just tie him up.
捆 捆著吧
In case he makes trouble again.
省去許多麻煩
Now, please take your buddy away!
帶走吧 你的好兄弟
Thank you, Your Highness!
謝謝少城主
Let's go! Come on!
走吧走吧走吧 走
What brought you here?
你怎麼來了
I heard you were dead and about to be buried here.
我聽說你死了 要葬在這兒
So I came to burn incense for you.
就想來給你上炷香
Who would expect something like this would happen?
誰知道趕上這麼一出
If I had known that, I would have come later.
早知道我就晚點來了
Maybe I could have really offered you some incense.
說不定 真的能給你上炷香呢
Can't believe I actually saved you!
居然把你給救了
Your bark is always worse than your bite.
刀子嘴 豆腐心
I know you wouldn't let me die.
我知道你捨不得我
You know me so well!
你倒是瞭解我
My fake death plan failed now.
如今 詐死的計劃被楚楚看破了
It's even harder for me to dodge Chuchu's attack in the future.
之後明槍易躲 暗箭難防了
Go to Xuanhu City with me.
你跟我回玄虎城吧
I'll take you to my home.
我帶你回家
From now on, you need not
以後花垣城的事
worry about what will happen in Huayuan.
和你再也沒有關係了
Let's go to Xuanhu City together!
咱們一起去玄虎城吧
No way!
不行
Who's that?
誰呀
He's a traveling merchant from Xuanhu City.
那個人是玄虎城的行商
He saved my life when I was badly injured.
我重傷的時候他救了我
We... We...
我們 我們
You are married?!
你成婚了
That's great! Let him come with us!
那好啊 叫過來一起
We can be each other's company on the way!
一路還能做伴
Call him over! Come on!
叫過來 叫過來
Who said I'd go with you?
誰要跟你們一起了
I have a husband now!
如今 我可是有夫君的人
So do I!
如今我也是有夫君的人